Thomas Strong

Summary

As a proven problem-solver my years of experience processing documents for publication, building spreadsheet calculators, and navigating software for scientific instruments (Scanning Electron Microscope, X-Ray Diffraction, SelFrag Lab, etc.), has shown me that coding is the ultimate tool of creation. I look forward to enriching and applying my development skills while devising solutions and creating environments and complex structures.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, C#, Typescript, YAML, C++

Technologies: Node.js, ReactJS, RESTful API, .NET, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Postman, Webpack

Other: Git, ArcGIS, Visual Basic, Jade 9, Minitab, NSS Spectral Imaging

> Education

Code Louisville Web Development II 2022 Web Development I 2022

Metropolitan State University of Denver B.S. Applied Geology (Cum Laude)

> Projects

FindMeABeer

June 2022 to July 2022

Single Page App - https://thomasstrong.github.io/beer-finder/

- Built via React boilerplate and State Hook.
- fetch() method for API request, parse in JSON.
- Full user search form with multiple input factors.

Monolith Lapidary

Feb. 2022 to Mar. 2022

Product Landing Site - https://thomasstrong.github.io/Monolith Lapidary/

- Employed ES6 solely to generate a product landing page.
- Utilized Flexbox and Grid to create a responsive site.
- Constructed with mobile-first programming.

CSS Memory Game

Apr. 2022

Game - https://thomasstrong.github.io/CSS_Memory_Game/

- CSS3 to create a fun game of Memory.
- Implemented dynamic Grid via vanilla JavaScript.
- Developed simple, responsive array for user choice.

> Employment

The Stave Restaurant & Bar Server/Bartender/Supervisor

Frankfort, KY

Oct. 2018 to Mar. 2020

- Consistently provided outstanding customer service through creative solutions leading to retention of repeat customers.
- Experience and excellent communication facilitated the maintenance of multiple roles as necessary for continued service.

United States Geological Survey (USGS) Denver, Colorado *Physical Scientist I* Jan. 2014 to Aug. 2018

- Created and maintained an extensive database (1,000+) of sample throughput that followed the internal life of samples and required collaboration between multiple agents.
- Established pre-analysis checks of samples through X-ray diffraction and X-ray fluorescence.
- Developed and published Standard Operating Procedures (SOP) for sample processing, which involved extensive testing of known and unknown methods. https://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/ofr20161022
- Constructed SOP for new equipment and provided concurrent development, as with high-voltage pulse power fragmentation (SelFrag Lab) for samples.
- Successfully captured and provided identification of samples via Scanning Electron Microscope and reflected and transmitted-light microscopes.